<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="10" moduleid="387" modulename="journal" contextid="648">
  <journal id="10">
    <name>Write a goal for yourself</name>
    <intro>&lt;div id="intro" class="generalbox box"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Set a goal for incorporating formative assessment strategies into your teaching practice. &lt;/span&gt;If you currently address and incorporate formative assessment strategies into your teaching, write a goal that increases your focus on formative assessment. The purpose of setting a goal is to help you have an end in mind, i.e., a way to refine your practice of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting &lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;our&lt;/span&gt; success as teachers to our students' success as learners is a hot topic these days in educational policy in K-12. What's a fair assessment of student learning? Here is an example from one of your peers in the cohort who combines student feedback on her instruction and their own learning with level gains based on standardized tests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing: &lt;/strong&gt;I would like to apply the writing improvement techniques and strategies I am learning in this course to the content of my classes. Assess after course completion which were effective, based upon my reflection and student feedback. I would like feedback from 50% of my students that they feel their writing has improved. I would also like them to witness level gains in their classes and progress in their meeting their own individual goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Math: &lt;/strong&gt;I would like to apply the math improvement techniques and strategies I am learning in this course to the content of my classes. Assess after course completion which were effective, based upon my reflection and student feedback. I would like feedback from 50% of my students that they feel their math has improved. I would also like them to witness level gains in their classes and progress in their meeting their own individual goals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you've learned more about the importance of &lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;goal setting&lt;/span&gt; to success, set your goal for using formative assessment in your teaching.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Write your goal so that it is tied to your circumstances, and reflective of your commitment to be a more effective teacher of adult students.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the &lt;a title="ABCDs of Goal Setting" href="$@PAGEVIEWBYID*389@$" target="_blank"&gt;ABCD's of good objectives&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;span style="font-family: 'verdana','sans-serif'; color: black; font-size: 11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <days>0</days>
    <grade>-4</grade>
    <timemodified>1521906833</timemodified>
    <entries>
    </entries>
  </journal>
</activity>