<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="122" moduleid="749" modulename="page" contextid="1115">
  <page id="122">
    <name>Face-to-Face Learning vs. Online Learning</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;What are some important differences between face-to-face workshops and asynchronous, discussionbased courses offered online? As you review the list of key differences, think about which of these differences is the most important to you, personally, and what you might do to help yourself be a successful online learner.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;What are some important differences between face-to-face workshops and asynchronous, discussion based courses offered online? As you review the list of key differences, think about which of these differences is the most important to you, personally, and what you might do to help yourself be a successful online learner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;SEQUENCING COURSE INFORMATION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float: left; margin-right: 10px;" alt="Topic Concerpt Model showing facts radiating out of topic concept theme" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_1.jpg" width="180" height="142" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;In a traditional classroom, the instructor or facilitator may choose from a wide variety of materials but presents the information in a linear fashion. However, in an online course, it is largely the participants who determine when and in what sequence they will access course information that is available to them (e.g., Web sites, lectures, readings, discussions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;ACCOMMODATING MULTIPLE LEARNING STYLES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float: right;" alt="Illustration: People learning in different ways" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_2.jpg" width="202" height="183" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Face-to-face, the instructor may employ a variety of means to deliver training, such as lectures, assigned readings, small-group discussions and task-based learning and other assignments. Online, the instructor and students may be more limited to the written word and would likely rely more heavily on writing and reading responses. To ward against this, online instructors can consciously incorporate different multimedia and collaborative, small-group activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;NATURE OF DISCUSSIONS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;img style="float: left;" alt="illustration: firecrackers exploding" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_3.jpg" width="126" height="113" /&gt;&lt;img style="float: right;" alt="photo: serene lake with mountains in distance" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_4.jpg" width="195" height="130" /&gt;Face-to-face classroom discussions have the potential to be spontaneous and lively, and discussions can take off suddenly in different directions, with unexpected comments or questions. Online, the discussions are more likely to be more reflective and perhaps consider a topic or issue more thoughtfully than in a classroom discussion; here participants have more time to ponder questions and comments posed by the instructor and respond to them when they are ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;CLASS PARTICIPATION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;img style="float: right;" alt="illustration: abstract faces talking" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_5.jpg" width="150" height="145" /&gt;In a face-to-face class, the instructor may make efforts to engage all participants, calling on individuals by name, for example, for an on-thespot response. Online, participants decide for themselves how actively they will take part in the course. They may interact in different times and even different in time zones, and thus not be participating as one whole group in real-time. The online instructor must take care to elicit comments from all students, including those who may be "quiet" or not very visible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;CLARIFYING MISUNDERSTANDINGS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;img style="float: left; margin-right: 10px;" alt="illustration: face questioning someone else." src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_6.jpg" width="150" height="155" /&gt;In a face-to-face class, body language (facial expressions, gestures, tone of voice) contributes a great deal to everyone's understanding of the messages conveyed and clarification can be immediate and brief. Online, in contrast, participants and facilitator alike may easily misinterpret the tone or intention of another's remark, and over time, misunderstandings can occur or can become exacerbated. Therefore, it is important for online learners to give the author of a remark the benefit of the doubt, and to follow simple rules of Netiquette, such as not using all capital letters (the equivalent of screaming at someone on the Internet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;ACCOMMODATING DIFFERENT PERSONALITIES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;img style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;" alt="photo: people talking in a group in a learning computer lab." src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_7.jpg" width="150" height="100" /&gt;In a face-to-face course, shy participants, or participants who perceive that their language proficiency is not as strong as that of their colleagues, may refrain from contributing much to class discussions. They may feel that more outgoing or outspoken participants dominate classroom conversations. Online, however, research shows that shy or less-proficient students tend to blossom, as they are given the time they need to formulate their thoughts and feel that they are on a more level playing field, so to speak. As well, discrimination related to age, gender, or other factors does not come into play as heavily in an online class, in which participants usually can neither see nor hear each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;COURSE DURATION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;img style="float: left; margin-right: 10px;" alt="illsutration: person sitting at desk with moon showing the time passing." src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_8.jpg" width="150" height="121" /&gt;Face-to-face classes meet for set periods of time and are relatively brief, compared to online classes. Online, participants need considerably more time to read and respond to comments made in class. Yet, by spanning a longer period of days or weeks, the online class has the potential to incorporate more reflection and practical application, as participants may relate what they are learning in class to what they are doing in the rest of their lives. This contrasts to the one-time workshop, which, research has shown, tends to have less impact on significantly changing a participant's actions. Here, for example, think of the one-off teacher development workshop and its ability to make a significant difference in how the teacher works with his or her learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: left;"&gt;ACCESS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;img style="float: right; margin-left: 10px;" alt="illustration: door opening to show the globe right outside" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/KeyDifferencesBetweenOnlineAndF2F_img_9.jpg" width="200" height="150" /&gt;Face-to-face classes are certainly more familiar to most participants than online courses, and depending on where the learners live and work, they may be easily accessed. However, as participants in professional development courses take on additional responsibilities (work, family and professional development), their schedules may become so impacted that it is nearly impossible to pursue further education. For those participants whose schedules do not easily permit taking a course at a regular schedule, online courses, which can be accessed 24 hours a day, seven days a week, from any computer with an Internet connection, can be a great boon. As well, for those participants who live in remote areas, or who are physically challenged, connecting to an online course may provide access to an education that would otherwise not be possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:1:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>12</revision>
    <timemodified>1405535419</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>